<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
	<title>The Practical Utopian</title>
	<description>Original Writings from The Practical Utopian</description>
	<link>https://practopian.org</link>
	<atom:link href="https://practopian.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<language>en-us</language>
	<managingEditor>hbowie@practopian.org (Herb Bowie)</managingEditor>
	<webMaster>hbowie@practopian.org (Herb Bowie)</webMaster>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00 PDT</lastBuildDate>
	<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
	<ttl>1440</ttl>
	<item>
		<title>Are Political Parties Doing Us More Harm Than Good?</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/are-political-parties-doing-us-more-harm-than-good.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/are-political-parties-doing-us-more-harm-than-good.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been making the case lately that the Republican Party is in decline, and needs to reinvent itself. But perhaps something even more radical is needed. For when we look at the current state of our two-party system in the US, nothing about it makes any sense. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>An Appreciation for And When I Die</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/appreciation/and-when-i-die.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/appreciation/and-when-i-die.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;As children, our thoughts about death are stuff of dreams and fairy tales. As adults we learn to suppress these thoughts because we are busy getting on with things. But as teenagers, in this transition between nursery rhymes and real life, we tend to approach this topic with a frankness and curiosity that can be somewhat startling. Laura Nyro wrote her song &amp;#8220;And When I Die&amp;#8221; at the age of 17, and her refreshing treatment of the subject shows none of the reverence or piety that we learn to adopt as adults. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Have Our Political Parties Turned Into Cults?</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/have-our-political-parties-turned-into-cults.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/have-our-political-parties-turned-into-cults.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a piece offering &amp;#8220;Some Hard-Won Wisdom Concerning Cults.&amp;#8221; And I&apos;ve written a couple of pieces recently questioning the direction of the current Republican Party. And so, today, I want to ask the question: should either, or both, of our political parties be considered cults? &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Some Hard-Won Wisdom Concerning Cults</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/some-hard-won-wisdom-concerning-cults.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/some-hard-won-wisdom-concerning-cults.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;As someone who once belonged to an organization later determined to be a cult, I can tell you that the warning signs are not always obvious. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Where, Exactly, Are the Republicans Headed?</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/where-exactly-are-the-republicans-headed.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/where-exactly-are-the-republicans-headed.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;So now the Republicans seem doomed to act like some strange variety of lemmings, unable to turn back from the cliff after their leader has jumped, but unable to turn away. And so they spend every day of their lives dancing along the edge, trying to convince the rest of us how good life will be at the bottom. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Leadership and Followership: 21 Key Observations</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/leadership-and-followership-21-key-observations.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/leadership-and-followership-21-key-observations.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;I was reading recently about a couple of different situations involving traits of both leadership and followership. Some reflection on these two situations has compelled me to dispense the following bits of wisdom on the subjects of leading and following. Some of these may seem obvious, and some controversial, but they are all equally true and valuable, based on my own experience doing a fair bit of both in a number of different organizations. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Thinking Differently About Our Economy</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/thinking-differently-about-our-economy.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/thinking-differently-about-our-economy.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;We all know that the economy is important. We talk about it every day. But do we ever think about&amp;#8230; how we think about it? How we visualize it? How we&apos;ve been conditioned to think about it, perhaps unknowingly? &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Importance of Progressive Activism</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-importance-of-progressive-activism.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-importance-of-progressive-activism.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;It was just a little over four years ago that I remember sitting in front of our TV with our neighbors, watching the election returns, preparing to celebrate. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Decline of the Republican Party - First Gradually and then Suddenly</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-decline-of-the-republican-party-first-gradually-and-then-suddenly.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-decline-of-the-republican-party-first-gradually-and-then-suddenly.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;In line with the famous quote from Ernest Hemingway, the Republican Party seems to see their fortunes on the decline &amp;#8211; gradually for now &amp;#8211; but perhaps suddenly before much longer. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Free Speech at the Crossroads</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/free-speech-at-the-crossroads.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/free-speech-at-the-crossroads.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;No matter where you stand on the political spectrum, questions surrounding free speech are hot-button items these days. Should anyone be free to say anything, about anyone, at any time, and to any audience? If not, who&apos;s responsible for moderation, and what are the rules? And at what point does moderation become censorship? &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>A Resumption of our Humanity</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/a-resumption-of-our-humanity.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/a-resumption-of-our-humanity.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;As I watched the Biden-Harris inaugural ceremonies this week, I found myself overcome by unanticipated thoughts and feelings. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Big Truth</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-big-truth.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-big-truth.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;If we want to end The Big Lie, what undisclosed pieces of truth do we need to bring out into the open in order to achieve a more spacious shared understanding of our common reality? &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Clown Coup</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-clown-coup.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-clown-coup.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;The invasion of our Capitol building on January 6th, 2021, and the accompanying disruption of the work of our duly elected members of Congress, was certainly an unprecedented and frightening addition to our American history books.  And yet, despite all of the terrifying and shocking things we witnessed during this day, the one thing we &lt;em&gt;didn&apos;t&lt;/em&gt; see was any serious attempt to seize power, or to overthrow our government. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Life is Complicated</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/life-is-complicated.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/life-is-complicated.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;We all would like a quick fix of simple certainty, and no matter where we turn today, we can find an army of pushers waiting to feed our habit, even giving the stuff away for free, just to keep us hooked. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Diving Back Into Our American Muddle</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/diving-back-into-our-american-muddle.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/diving-back-into-our-american-muddle.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m tempted to call the story heartbreaking, but it&apos;s more like brain-breaking: how can people who are so sick that they have to be hospitalized still refuse to believe in the existence of the very disease that is killing them? &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>An Appreciation for Hallelujah</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/appreciation/hallelujah.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/appreciation/hallelujah.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;The history of Leonard Cohen&apos;s song &amp;#8220;Hallelujah&amp;#8221; is a fascinating one. Cohen&apos;s songs had never really been embraced by the masses, and his first recording of &amp;#8220;Hallelujah&amp;#8221; in the early eighties was part of an album so lacking in obvious commercial appeal that the president of CBS Records responded to it by saying: &amp;#8220;What is this? This isn&apos;t pop music. We&apos;re not releasing it. This is a disaster.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Reframing our Debates about Capitalism</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/reframing-our-debates-about-capitalism.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/reframing-our-debates-about-capitalism.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;There is a flaw in the reasoning behind our infernal, never-ending, society-splitting debate concerning socialism vs. capitalism, and I want to point it out. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Era of Environmental Accommodation is Over</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-era-of-environmental-accommodation-is-over.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-era-of-environmental-accommodation-is-over.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;When historians look at the long span of our human history, they try to make sense of our arc of cultural evolution by breaking it up into phases. There are multiple perspectives we can use for this sort of exercise, but the most important is the relationship of our human population to the rest of our world. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Shocking Truth About Us Liberals</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-shocking-truth-about-us-liberals.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-shocking-truth-about-us-liberals.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;I can tell from my occasional conversations with friends and relatives who vote Republican that they have been thoroughly brainwashed about what we liberals stand for in the modern era. So let me lift the veil of secrecy and reveal some of our deepest, darkest secrets. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Undoing Trumpism</title>
		<link>https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/undoing-trumpism.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://practopian.org/blog/hbowie/undoing-trumpism.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;With a little luck, and a lot of hard work, we might be fortunate enough to see Donald Trump leave office in a few months. If so, that will be the end of the Trump presidency. Unfortunately, though, it won&apos;t mean the end of Trumpism. &lt;/p&gt;

		</description>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
